Bhuvaneswari Subramani

DEVOPS SPECIALIST · CLOUD ARCHITECT · LEADER

Bangalore, India

■ bhuvaneswari.subramani@gmail.com | 🏕 bhuvana.pro | 🛅 bhuvanas | 💆 @installjournal

"Be the change that you want to see in the world."

Summary.

A Visionary leader with 2 decades of IT experience specialized in DevOps (covering Build & Release Automation, ALM Tools Administration, Cloud Migration) and Performance QA at scale. Bhuvaneswari is a Cloud enthusiast with hands-on experience in Digital Cloud Transformation to gain insights and capitalize, Cloud Native Architectures. Thirst for innovation & keen interest in latest trends and technologies, stands strong for her to implement modernization strategy in achieving corporate objectives.

Bhuvaneswari is a technophile & IT Blogger for over a decade, who passionately writes exemplary tech blogs on DevOps & CloudComputing and an active speaker at AWS community events, industry conferences & engineering colleges. Thirst for innovation Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies.

Work Experience

Infor Bangalore, India

DIRECTOR, ENGINEERING OPERATIONS

Oct. 2012 - Present

- Delivered 50+ major releases for Infor Nexus product suite with in-numerous feature automation's and integration's seamlessly propagated through DevOps pipeline all the way from Dev, Test, PreProd to Prod Environments.
- Coach, develop and mentor a multi-disciplinary team of engineers responsible for DevOps, PerfQA, Cloud IaC Development & ALM Tools Administration.
- Developing and deploying complex applications on Hybrid, Private & Public Cloud
- Design, setup, and maintain Application Lifecycle Management (ALM) tools with disaster recovery strategy documentation and Simulated.
- Cultivate strong cross-organizational partnerships with peers and stakeholders to drive feature automation & propagate changes from Dev, Test, PreProd and Prod Environments.
- · Ensuring visibility, traceability, and control of performance testing process to deliver high-quality software
- Revitalized teams including peer programming, continuous integration (Jenkins), continuous delivery models, standardized environments, behavioral driven testing, and continuous collaboration.
- Takes appropriate proactive actions to insure all systems are functioning optimally to fulfill required business needs
- Proven multi-tasker with strong public-speaking, writing, critical thinking & analytical skills.

Aptean (formerly CDC Software)

Bangalore, India

MANAGER, CONFIGURATION MANAGEMENT

Aug. 2006 - Sep. 2016

- Worked on end to end Application Packaging, Build Automation, Deployment to Sandbox machines & Software Configuration for ERP, CRM and
 related products, catering the needs of multiple agile Teams.
- Established "best practices", devised & implemented process documents for authoring / maintaining Setup packages, merge modules, upgrades, patches and extended support for large scale deployment through ADS & SMS.
- Administered and maintained Source Control Repositories, devised various disaster recovery processes for Source Control Systems like Vault, TFS, Seapine Surround.
- Constant interaction with Product Management, Development and QA teams in the worldwide offices right from Requirement Study to Product Release.
- · Hiring, onboarding, mentoring and training great engineers.

Synaptris Decisions Chennai, India

BUILD & RELEASE ENGINEER

Design and developed installers for IntelligitEW suits of products developed using Net 9 Delphi

July. 2005 - Aug. 2006

- Design and developed installers for IntelliVIEW suite of products developed using .Net & Delphi.
- Design and co-ordinated the development of IntelliVIEW Reporter (Java Source) 3.5 Installer for Windows, Linux & Solaris.
- · Automated the Build Process for all the products (including Release versions and upgrade), using Batch Scripts and VBScripts.
- Evaluated several Build Automation tools and implemented FinalBuilder for the IntelliVIEW Products.

Sonata Software Ltd Bangalore, India

SENIOR SYSTEM ANALYST

Apr. 2004 - May. 2005

• Developed & maintained multi-platform installer for Team Developer 2005 & related products compatible with all flavours of Windows & Linux

- Created customized installer to check for the existence of Crossover / install Custom Crossover & configure for Linux, which helps to install
 Windows based Team Developer on Linux platform
- · Implemented unattended & console mode installation for both Windows & Universal Installer.

Bannari Infotech Private Ltd Coimbatore, India

PROJECT LEADER Jun 2000 - Apr 2004

 Design and developed GIS based desktop applications for Radio based Active Vehcile Tracking System (TripMapp) using VB & MS Access and GSM based online vechile trackingsystem (TRIPTRAK)

- Design and developed GIS based web applications OPTITRACK, MINE TRACK, ActiveTRAK.
- Packaged Smartcard & GIS Based desktop applications using InstallShield Developer 7.0
- · Enhanced & maintained eseebargain.com, a B2B portal and involved System Testing & Integration Testing.

Education & Certification

MKU Madurai, India

MBA IN INFORMATION SYSTEMS

2001 - 2003

· First Class.

BIT Sathy Sathyamangalam, India

B.E. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

1996 - 2000

• Distinction. Secured university rank in several subjects

Certifications

 Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals, Microsoft Certified Azure Architecting Technologies Sep. 2020 • AWS Certified Security - Speciality Aug. 2020 • AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate & Professional May. 2019

Honors & Awards

INTERNATIONAL

Nov. 2020 AWS DevTools Hero, Amazon Web Services Seatle, U.S.A Jun. 2020 Infor Security Hero, Infor New York, U.S.A Mar. 2020 Spotlight on Infor Women, Infor New York, U.S.A Jun. 2019 AWS Community Hero, Amazon Web Services Seatle, U.S.A Feb 2019 WomenOfInfor, Infor New York, U.S.A Oct. 2018 AWS re:Invent User Group leader diversity scholarship recipients for 2018, Amazon Web Services Seatle, U.S.A

DOMESTIC

Mar. 2018 Alumnae Excellence Award from Alma Mater, BIT Sathy Sathy, India Oct. 2014 Spot Award for swiftly delivering multi-platform installers for Gupta Team Developer, Sonata Software Bangalore, India Apr. 2007 Extra Mile for best effort in Ross ERP Installer packaging, Aptean Bangalore, India Oct. 2000 Silver Medal for bagging 3rd place in Computer Science Department, BIT Sathy Sathy, India

Community, Events, Activities

BIT Sathy Alumnae Bangalore Chapter

Bangalore, India

CORE MEMBER & SECRETARY

AWS User Group

Nov. 2014 - Present

Revitalizing powerful alumnae network to give back to the society & institution in the best possible way

Bangalore, India Oct. 2019 - Present

AWS DevTools Hero & Organizer Bengaluru

- Organize & host AWS Community Day, monthly meetups and Hackathon for Good
- · Active speaker at AWS community events, & industry conferences across globe & Engineering Colleges
- Judge for International Women Only hackathon 2019 organized by Hackerearth
- Slides from my various guest lectures and presentations

Skills_

- Programming: Python, Shell Script, SaltStack, HTML (past experience VB 6.0, Java, InstallScript, VBScript, ASP. Net, VB.Net, ASP, VBScript, JavaScript)
- Technical Specialities: AWS Cloud Services, Serverless, AWS CloudFormation, SaltStack, Terraform, Jenkins, AWS Developer Tools, Docker, Splunk, Docker, Splunk, UFT, LoadRunner, JMeter, Jira, Git, Confluence (past experience SVN, TFS, Seapine Surround, Vault, & Bugzilla, Application Packaging using Windows Installer (MSI), InstallShield (IS) & WiX Installer, AutoDesk Map Guide Server, Author & Viewer 5.0,)